[
     {
        "question":"\\text{center of mass for point masses}",
        "answer":"r_{com}\\;=\\;\\frac{m_1r_1+m_2r_2}{m_1+m_2}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{for two masses. }r_1\\;,\\;r_2\\text{ special property}",
        "answer":"m_1r_1=m_2r_2\\;and\\;r_1=\\frac{m_{2}r}{m_{1}+m_{2}}\\;and\\;r_2=\\frac{m_{1}r}{m_{1}+m_{2}}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{for any extended body r_{com}=?",
        "answer":"r_{com}= \\frac{∫x.dm}{∫dm}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM for rod}",
        "answer":"\\frac{L}{2}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM for semi circular ring}",
        "answer":"\\frac{2R}{\\pi}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM for semi circular disk}",
        "answer":"\\frac{4R}{3\\pi}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM of annular semi circular ring}",
        "answer":"\\frac{4}{3\\pi}(\\frac{r^3_2-r^3_1}{r^2_2-r^2_1})"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM of arc of a ring}",
        "answer":"\\frac{2R}{\\theta}sin(\\frac{\\theta}{2})"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM of sector of a plate}",
        "answer":"\\frac{R sin(\\theta)}{3\\theta}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM of solid cone}",
        "answer":"\\frac{3h}{r}\\;(from\\;apex)"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COMhollow cone}",
        "answer":"\\frac{2h}{3}\\;(from\\;apex)"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM of solid hemisphere}",
        "answer":"\\frac{3R}{8}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM of hollow hemisphere}",
        "answer":"\\frac{R}{2}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{COM of tringular lamina}",
        "answer":"\\text{at centroid}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{V_{com}",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"a_{com}",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"△r_{com}",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"F_{net}\\;=\\;M_{total}a_{com}\\;and\\;P_{net}\\;=\\;M_{total}V_{com}}",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{value of e}",
        "answer":"\\frac{v_2-v_1}{u_1-u_2}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{aagar e ≠ 1 then kinetic energy loss hogi after collision .}K_{loss}=?",
        "answer":"K_{loss}\\;=\\;\\frac{1}{2}(\\frac{m_1m_2}{m_1+m_2})U_{rel}^{2}(1-e^2)"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{thrust force}",
        "answer":"F\\;=\\;v_{rel}\\frac{dm}{dt}\\;(\\text{where }\\frac{dm}{dt}\\text{ is mass ejection rate})"
    }
]
